Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Computer Science
3400 N Charles St
Baltimore, MD 21218, USA
killeen@jhu.edu

Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am interested in intelligent surgical systems that improve patient outcomes. My recent work involves realistic simulation of interventional X-ray imaging for the purpose of developing Al-integrated surgical systems. I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL).

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.

08/2019 - present
With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

B.A., Computer Science with Honors, Minor in Physics, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019 Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis

With Gordon Kindlmann.

Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

Research Assistant, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, 08/2019 - 06/2020 Baltimore, MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019 With Gordon Kindlmann.

Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA.

06/2020 - 07/2020

With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.

Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.

06/2017 - 08/2017

Selected Honors

With Geoffrey Burr.

Runner-up, **Physics of Medical Imaging Best Student Paper Award**For paper [C-5] at SPIE Medical Imaging 2022.

Best Paper Award in Bioengineering

For paper [C-4] at IEEE BIBE 2021.

Best Presentation Award

O4/2021

In Reliable Software Systems at Johns Hopkins University.

Best Graduate Project Award

O5/2020
In Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology II at Johns Hopkins University.

COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle 04/2020
For the dataset in [M-1].

12/2019

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award.

For Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks in Deep Learning at Johns

For Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks in Deep Learning at Johns Hopkins University.

Publications

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar. Unless otherwise noted, (*) denotes equal contribution.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles	A. Hundt, B. Killeen , H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.	J-2
	S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini, N. Farinha, B. Killeen , C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.	J-1
Peer-reviewed Conference Papers	B. D. Killeen , Shreya Chakraborty, Greg Osgood, Mathias Unberath. Toward perception-based anticipation of cortical breach during K-wire fixation of the pelvis. Medical Imaging 2022: Physics of Medical Imaging. SPIE. doi: 10.1117/12.2612989.	C-5
	- Runner-up, SPIE Medical Imaging Physics of Medical Imaging Best Student Paper Award	
	J. D. Opfermann*, B. D. Killeen *, C. Bailey, M. Khan, A. Uneri, K. Suzuki, M. Armand, F. Hui, A. Krieger**, M. Unberath**. Feasibility of a Cannula-mounted Piezo Robot for Image-guided Vertebral Augmentation: Toward a Low Cost, Semi-autonomous Approach. 2021 IEEE 21st International Conference on Bioinformatics and Bioengineering (BIBE), Kragujevac, Serbia, 2021 pp. 1-8. doi: 10.1109/BIBE52308.2021.9635356. *Joint first authors; ** joint last authors.	C-4
	- Honored with Best Paper Award in Bioengineering.	
	X. Liu*, B. D. Killeen *, A. Sinha, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Neighborhood Normalization for Robust Geometric Feature Learning. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2021. *Joint first authors listed alphabetically.	n C-3
	C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, B. D. Killeen , M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registrationc. MICCAI, 2020, arxiv:2003.10987.	C-2
	X. Liu, Y. Zhang, B. Killeen , M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.	C-1
Preprints	J. Y. Wu*, B. D. Killeen *, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath. Changes in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687.	M-2
	B. D. Killeen* , J. Y. Wu*, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756.	M-1
Patents	G. W. Burr and B. D. Killeen . 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020, uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986.	P-1
Selected Press	Dziarkach, Andrei. "Details with Andrei Dziarkach." Voice of America. November 21, 2020 Accessed November 26, 2020. golosameriki.com/a/detali/5671254.html. Rosen, Jill. "Dog Training Methods Plub Teach Robots to Learn New Tricks." The Johns Hopkins University Hub. The Johns Hopkins Plub Plub Plub Plub Plub Plub Plub Plub	2020
	hub.jhu.edu/2020/10/26/positive-reinforcement-for-robots	
Teaching		
Supervision	I have supervised a number of talented masters and undergraduate students on research projects and theses:	
	Sean Darcy, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.	10/2021 - present
	Zidi Tao, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.	10/2021 - present
	Nethra Venkatayogi, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX, USA.	05/2021 - 10/2021
	Max Judish, Brown University, Providence, RI, USA.	01/2021 - 08/2021
	Shreya Chakraborty, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. Now at PathAI.	08/2020 - 09/2021

12/2019 - 03/2020

Philipp Nikutta, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany. Now at Argo Al.

With Russ Taylor and Emad Boctor.

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of

Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.

With Yali Amit.

Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions.

Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful."

More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda

Grading Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA

01/2019 - 08/2019

03/2019 - 06/2019

- Scientific Visualization
- Introduction to Computer Science I
- Introduction to Computer Science II

Tutoring Topics in Computer Science, Machine Learning, Baltimore, MD, USA.

06/2020 - present

We have explored numerous topics, including differential calculus, neural networks, computer vision, natural language processing, and functional programming.

Service

Professional Sports Officer, MICCAI Society Student Board

12/2021 - present

Graduate Student Committee Representative, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics 09/2020 - present

Head of Student Resources

Community Family Member, Thread, Baltimore, MD, USA.

06/2021 - present

I volunteer with students at Douglass High School in Baltimore City, helping with algebra or physics homework, organizing social outings, and assiting with graduation requirements.

Volunteer Instructor, CompileHer, Chicago, IL, USA.

2019

Peer Review - IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)

2021-2022

- Nature Scientific Data 2020

Selected Coursework

Graduate Vision as Bayesian Inference

GPA: 3.82

Reliable Software Systems
Theory of Computation
Parallel Programming
Nonlinear Optimization II
Computer Integrated Surgery II
Computer Integrated Surgery I

Deep Learning

Undergraduate Unsupervised Learning*

GPA: 3.81

Computer Vision

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis

Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms

Honors Discrete Mathematics Scientific Visualization Programming Languages

Networks and Distributed Systems Quantum Mechanics I \& II

Intermediate Mechanics

Electronics Wizards

*Graduate level.

Memberships

International Society for Optics and Photonics (SPIE) Student Member

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Graduate Student Member

Extracurricular

Outside of the office, I enjoy bouldering, cycling, running, and painting. I also write creatively:

Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.com/blog

Science fiction.

Metadata

This document is available

- online: benjamindkilleen.com/markdown-cv.
- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: April 2022